Imogen Cunningham
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Thomas, Michael: Jun 23, 1973*; Sep 26, 1974; Oct 03, 1974*
Thomas, Randy: see Mind's Eye
Thompson, Carol: see California: University of California at Berkeley
Thomson, Kristyne: May 13, 1974*
Tice, George: May 23, 1970; Mar 24, 1975*
Tice, Opal: Apr 21, 1967*
Time, Inc.: Dec 09, 1969*; Oct 13, 1975
Time-Life Books: Oct 11, 1969*; Dec 04, 1969; Dec 10, 1969; Dec 15, 1969; Feb 03, 1970; Feb 10, 1970; Feb 12, 1970*; Apr 13, 1970*; May 28, 1970*; Jul 19, 1970*; Aug 29, 1970*; Apr 30, 1971*; Jun 30, 1971*; Nov 16, 1971; Nov 19, 1971*; Nov 29, 1974*
Tintype Photography Center: Jul 13, 1971; Jul 19, 1971*
TIO Fotografer: Jul 14, 1961
Todd, Jeannette: Mar 15, 1965; Oct 04, 1974
Toelle, Alan D.: Mar 09, 1967
Toklas, Alice B.: Dec 22, 1952*; Jan 07, 1953; Oct 21, 1954*; Nov 07, 1954; Jun 12, 1960; Sep 06, 1964*
Tomoko, Bobby: Jan 02, 1965
TONIGHT SHOW: Mar 24, 1976*; Apr 13, 1976; Apr 21, 1976*; also see Photographs
Toth, Dr. Tas: Nov 04, 1966; Jan 25, 1967*
Troeller, Linda: Jul 10, 1973
Trumbull, Harlan and Dorothy: Apr 27, 1965; Jul 09, 1965*; Jul 19, 1965; Apr 05, 1968; May 13, 1974*; May 17, 1974
Tucker, Anne: Jan 24, 1974
Tucker, Kay: Nov 14, [1968]; Nov 17, 1968; Sep 18, 1973 (including a photograph of Yankee Beach)
Turnage, Bill: Oct 22, 1974*; Oct 30, 1974; also see Adams: Ansel Adams Gallery
Tuttle, Lyle: undated
Tynan, Kenneth (The New Yorker): Jan 29, 1960
Ulman, Elinor: undated (5); Apr 10, 1968*; Jan 26, 1971*; Mar 17, 1972*; [Apr 05, 1974]; Apr 05, 1974*; Sep 07, 1974*; Sep 27, 1974; Nov 17, 1974*; Feb 29, 1975
Ulrich, David: Sep 07, 1972; Sep 26, 1972*
U.S. Camera magazine (Tom Maloney): Apr 05, 1940*; Aug 25, 1941; Sep 02, 1941*; Feb 10, 1954; Mar 29, 1954; Apr 08, 1955*; Apr 30, 1956*; Jun 29, 1957*; Jan 12, 1959; Jan 19, 1959*; Jan 1969; Feb 27, 1969*; Oct 12, 1969* (2); also see Vestal, David
United States Information Agency: Jan 14, 1961*; Apr 04, 1961; Dec 26, 1961; Jun 06, 1971*
Unte_____, Liesel: Jul 08, 1968*
Unteutsch, Liesel: May 1, 1969* (in German)
Untitled (gallery): May 04, 1976; May 13, 1976*; Jul 19, 1976 (letter of condolence to Gryffyd Partridge)
Valeska, Lette: Sep 20, 1973; Oct 20, 1973*
Valvo, Ninfa: see Stanford University
Vanasse, Sally: Apr 30, 1969
Van der Zee, John: May 27, 1972*; also see International Museum of Photography
Van Dyke, Milton: Dec 23, 1969 (photo Christmas card)
Van Dyke, Willard: Jul 28, 1947*; Apr 28, 1957*; Nov 05, 1960; Dec 15, 1960; Sep 14, 1965; Dec 01, 1966; May 14, 1967*; Jun 11, 1967; Feb 02, 1968*; Feb 17, 1968; May 15, 1968; May 19, 1968*; Jul 05, 1968*; Jul 11, 1968; Mar 16, 1970*; Apr 13, 1970*; Feb 07, 1972*; Dec 07, 1972*; May 03, 1973; [Feb 06, 1974]*; Feb 06, 1974*; Nov 25, 1974; May 11, 1975*; Jun 28, 1976 (letter of condolence to Gryffyd Partridge); also see Museum of Modern Art
Vanity Fair: May 09, 1935; Jun 10, 1935*; Jun 13, 1935
Van Meter, Bruce and Barbie: undated (2); Mar 04, 1968*; Feb 17, 1969*; Sep 19, 1969; Dec 25, 1969; Dec 29, 1969*; Mar 08, 1971; Mar 11, 1971*; Jul 25, 1971*; Aug 03, 1971; Dec 05, 1971*; Apr 29, 1976*
Vaughan, Carolyn H.: May 21, 1971; Dec 10, 1971; Dec 15, 1971*; Jan 17, 1972; Jan 21, 1972*; Feb 03, 1974* (letter of recommendation)
Vera (the designer): Mar 21, 1961*
Vestal, David: Apr 23, 1969*; Dec 08, 1969
Vignes, Michelle: Sep 30, 1974
Viking Press: Dec 13, 1956*; Jan 07, 1957
Virginia Slims Books of Days: May 22, 1973; Jun 07, 1973*
Visual Dialogue Foundation: Mar 16, 1970*
Vodman, Mary Ann: Aug 25, 1973; Mar 28, 1974*
Voelckers, Frau: Jul 31, 1947*; Jun 28, 1948; Jul 02, 1949*; Aug 14, 1949*; Feb 27, 1950*; Nov 27, 1950*; Aug 01, 1952*; Jan 09, 1953*; Dec 08, 1954*; Jan 14, 1955; Dec 26, 1955*
Voelckers, Renate: Dec 24, 1969*
Volckers, Maria Therese: Dec 20, 1958; Jan 11, 1959*; Jul 13, 1961 (in German); Jun 10, 1965*
Volunteer Service Photographers: Dec 1974
Vondras, Radek: undated
von Probpsoc.?, Jan: Aug 06, 1969*
von Sonnenburg: see Falkner von Sonnenburg, Erwin
Voyages: [Aug 12, 1968]; Dec 23, 1968*; Dec 31, 1968; Jan 06, 1969*; Jan 08, 1969; Mar 12, 1969*; Mar 26, 1969
Voystock, Thomas: May 1973
Wagstaff, Samuel: Apr 11, 1975; Apr 16, 1975*
Wahrhaftig, Alma: Jun 20, 1976
Wahrhaftig, Clyde: Jun 09, 1957; Aug 20, 1957
Waite, Esther: Jul 22, 1976
Walkinshaw, Jean: undated
Walsh, Elsa: Aug 12, 1960; Aug 30, 1965; Oct 06, 1965*; Jan 19, 1971; Oct 06, 1972*; Oct 10, 1972*; mentioned in letter dated Jun 18, 1973; Jun 25, 1973*; Jun 30, 1973; May 27, 1975*; Jul 06, 1976 (letter of condolence to Gryffyd Partridge)
Warden, J. E.: Aug 07, 1947
Warnecke: John Carl Warnecke and Associates: May 16, 1961; Dec 01, 1961; Dec 01, 1961*; Apr 25, 1962*; Jul 19, 1962; Jul 08, 1963*
Washington: University of Washington, Seattle: Jan 20, 1965; Feb 02, 1965; Mar 03, 1965; Mar 09, 1965*; Mar 12, 1965; Mar 19, 1965*; May 14, 1965; Mar 19, 1965*; Jul 28, 1965; Jun 21, 1967*; Jan 22, 1970*; Mar 14, 1974; Mar 26, 1974*; Apr 24, 1974; May 17, 1974*; Jun 03, 1974; Jun 21, 1974; Jun 25, 1974; also see Henry Gallery; also see Photographs
Washington: University of Washington Alumni Association: Feb 27, 1974; Mar 01, 1974*; Apr 04, 1974; Apr 29, 1974; May 05, 1974*; May 06, 1974*; May 10, 1974; May 14, 1974*; Jun 05, 1974*; Jul 25, 1974; Aug 03, 1974*
Washington: University of Washington Libraries: May 06, 1976
Washington: University of Washington Press: Jul 12, 1965; Jul 24, 1965*; Jul 26, 1965; Jul 29, 1965*; Jul 30, 1965; Sep 21, 1965; Oct 23, 1965*; Mar 16, 1966; Apr 04, 1966*; May 10, 1967; Sep 25, 1967; Sep 29, 1967; Apr 30, 1968; May 09, 1968*; Sep 29, 1968*; Oct 10, 1968; Nov 04, 1968*; Feb 26, 1969*; Apr 16, 1969; Apr 29, 1969; Apr 30, 1969*; Jun 19, 1969 (including contract); Jul 14, 1969*; Jul 18, 1969; Sep 15, 1969*; Sep 17, 1969*; Sep 22, 1969; Oct 08, 1969*; Oct 27, 1969; Nov 21, 1969; Nov 25, 1969*; Dec 09, 1969; Dec 23, 1969*; Jan 02, 1970; Jan 22, 1970*; Jan 27, 1970; Apr 09, 1970; Apr 26, 1970*; Apr 30, 1970; May 16, 1970*; May 18, 1970; Jun 17, 1970*; Jul 05, 1970*; Jul 28, 1970*; Aug 04, 1970; Aug 11, 1970*; Aug 14, 1970; Sep 14, 1970*; Sep 22, 1970; Sep 22, 1970*; Sep 30, 1970*; Oct 07, 1970; Oct 11, 1970*; Oct 14, 1970; Oct 15, 1970; Oct 16, 1970*; Oct 30, 1970; Nov 06, 1970*; Nov 16, 1970; Nov 17, 1970; Nov 20, 1970; Nov 26, 1970; Dec 07, 1970*; Dec 11, 1970; Dec 23, 1970*; Dec 28, 1970; Jan 05, 1971; Jan 16, 1971*; Jan 19, 1971; Feb 08, 1971*; Feb 10, 1971 (2); Feb 16, 1971*; Feb 23, 1971; Mar 11, 1971*; Mar 17, 1971; Mar 15, 1971*; Mar 29, 1971; May 02, 1971*; May 04, 1971; Jun 01, 1971; Jun 09, 1971*; Jun 16, 1971; Jun 22, 1971; Jun 27, 1971*; Jul 01, 1971; [Jul 01, 1971]*; Sep 13, 1971*; Sep 17, 1971; Feb 29, 1972*; Mar 02, 1973; Mar 28, 1973*; Apr 04, 1973; Oct 01, 1973; Nov 26, 1973; Dec 31, 1973*; Jan 10, 1974; Jan 21, 1974*; Jan 27, 1974 (including contract); Feb 05, 1974; Feb 09, 1974*; Feb 20, 1974; Mar 07, 1974*; Mar 13, 1974; Mar 30, 1974*; Apr 01, 1974; Apr 18, 1974; May 05, 1974*; May 07, 1974; May 24, 1974*; May 29, 1974 (2); Jun 03, 1974*; Sep 22, 1974*; Oct 25, 1974*; Oct 29, 1974; Oct 31, 1974; Dec 22, 1974*; Dec 26, 1974; Jan 07, 1975; Jan 27, 1975; Feb 02, 1975*; May 12, 1975; May 29, 1975*; Oct 16, 1975; Jan 09, 1976; Jan 14, 1976; Feb 27, 1976; Mar 17, 1976; Mar 23, 1976; Apr 19, 1976*; May 20, 1976; Jun 04, 1976; Jun 24, 1976
Watkins, Malcolm and Joan: Mar 13, 1969; Apr 14, 1969*; Sep 10, 1970*; Oct 24, 1970; Oct 25, 1970*; Oct 26, 1970*; Feb 15, 1971*
Watterston, Henning: Dec 11, 1948*; Feb 10, 1949*; Feb 21, 1949*; Mar 18, 1949*; Aug 01, 1949*; Nov 19, 1949*; May 22, 1950*; Dec 04, 1951*; Jan 12, 1954*; Jan 03, 1956*; Feb 22, 1971; Feb 26, 1971*
Weaver, Gay: Jun 01, 1974
Webb, Lucille and Todd: Dec 11, 1971 (including photograph of the Webbs)
Weber, Al: Apr 12, 1971
Wehr, Wesley: Feb 06, 1974
Welpott, Jack: Nov 27, 1971* (letter of recommendation); mentioned in letter dated May 15, 1974
Werling, Bob: Mar 12, 1972*; May 29, 1972*; Mar 29, 1974*; Sep 04, 1974; Apr 28, 1975*; May 22, 1975*; Jan 1976; Apr 16, 1976*
Wessels, Glenn: Jan 05, 1968
West Coast Airlines: Jun 07, 1966; Jun 11, 1966*; Jun 14, 1966; Jun 20, 1966*; Jun 21, 1966; Jul 01, 1966; Nov 09, 1966*; Nov 14, 1966; Nov 30, 1966; Dec 08, 1966*; Dec 11, 1966*; Jan 26, 1967*; Jul 26, 1967; Jan 04, 1968; Jan 09, 1968*
Western Association of Art Museums: Feb 02, 1967*; Feb 22, 1967; Feb 25, 1967*; Mar 02, 1967; Mar 17, 1967*; Feb 19, 1976 (2)
Western Family: Oct 1955
Weston, Edward: Jan 12, 1928 (photocopy)
Wheat, Beth: undated
Whistler Productions: May 02, 1974*
White House Cultural Affairs Office: Dec 06, 1969
White, Maynard (Clarence White's nephew): Jun 28, 1974
White, Minor: undated; Apr 02, 1951; Jul 20, 1951 (including a typescript re the Albert M. Bender Trust); Mar 08, 1954*; Mar 25, 1954; Jul 07, 1954*; Jul 16, 1954; Jul 28, 1954*; Aug 03, 1954; Aug 09, 1954*; Sep 07, 1954; Oct 21, 1954*; Oct 25, 1954; Nov 12, 1954*; Feb 10, 1955*; Feb 22, 1955; Aug 10, 1955; Aug 21, 1955*; Aug 26, 1955; Jan 23, 1956; Mar 01, 1956*; Mar 02, 1956; Mar 18, 1956*; Mar 22, 1956; Jan 23, 1957; Mar 11, 1957*; Mar 13, 1957; Mar 20, 1957; Mar 28, 1957*; Apr 02, 1957*; Apr 03, 1957; Apr 10, 1957; Apr 29, 1957*; May 10, 1957; May 14, 1957*; Jun 24, 1957*; Sep 12, 1957*; Jan 05, 1958; Jan 15, 1958; Feb 12, 1958*; Feb 23, 1958; Apr 06, 1958*; Sep 07, 1958*; Sep 13, 1958; Jun 01, 1959*; Oct 23, 1959; Nov 20, 1959*; Dec 12, 1959; Dec 20, 1959*; Dec 28, 1959; Feb 25, 1961; Mar 10, 1961*; Apr 1961; Dec 26, 1962; Feb 28, 1963*; Apr 02, 1963 (2); May 07, 1963; Nov 12, 1963; Feb 23, 1964; Mar 19, 1964; Mar 24, 1964; Mar 28, 1964*; Apr 01, 1964; Apr 04, 1964; Apr 21, 1964; Apr 30, 1964*; May 20, 1964*; Jun 11, 1964; Aug 10, 1964*; Sep 27, 1964*; Nov 26, 1964*; Dec 08, 1964; Dec 20, 1964*; Feb 13, 1965; Jun 11, 1965*; Jun 23, 1965*; Jul 13, 1965; Dec 08, 1966*; Jan 09, 1967; Jan 20, 1967*; Feb 22, 1967*; May 26, 1967*; Jan 10, 1968; Jan 26, 1968; Jan 29, 1968; Feb 02, 1968*; Feb 14, 1968*; Feb 15, 1968; Feb 25, 1968; Mar 25, 1968; Apr 02, 1968* (2); Apr 11, 1968; May 20, 1968; Aug 09, 1968*; Jan 01, 1969; May 03, 1969*; Jan 13, 1970*; Jan 16, 1970; May 07, 1970* (2); Aug 30, 1970*; Sep 27, 1970*; Oct 05, 1970; Oct 09, 1970*; Nov 05, 1970*; Nov 17, 1970; Aug 09, 1971*; Oct 07, 1971; Feb 29, 1972*; Mar 21, 1972; Dec 04, 1973; Dec 23, 1973*; Jan 07, 1974; Jan 17, 1974; Jan 13, 1975*; mentioned in letter dated Mar 14, 1976; Apr 10, 1976; also see Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Whitney Museum of American Art: Mar 11, 1959; Mar 14, 1959*; Jun 01, 1973; Jun 13, 1973*; Jul 23, 1973; Sep 21, 1973; Nov 13, 1973; Mar 20, 1974; Apr 22, 1974*; May 07, 1974; Nov 26, 1974; Feb 19, 1975; Feb 24, 1975
Wiggins, Jim: [Sep 23, 1972]; Sep 23, 1972*; Dec 12, [1972]
Wigh, Leif: see Writings
Wilcox, Jeduthan: Oct 16, 1971; Nov 08, 1971*; Nov 24, 1971; Nov 26, 1971*
Wildenhain, Marguerite: Feb 08, 1955; Feb 28, 1955*
Willard, Marian: Nov 23, 1956
Williams, Jonathan: Jan 20, 1971; Apr 10, 1971
Williams, Shedrick: see Shad's Gallery
Williams, Tina: Jun 25, 1963*
Williamson, Irene: Jan 08, 1971*; Mar 22, 1971*; Aug 22, 1977
Willis, Elizabeth Bayley: Nov 10, 1970
Wilson, Adrian and Joyce Lancaster: Dec 26, 1965; Feb 18, 1975 (letter from Cunningham's lawyers, Morrison & Foerster)
Wilson, Nicholas: Dec 19, 1973 (including 23 picture postcards)
Winkler, John (Wink): Jan 05, 1952; Jul 26, 1958; Jan 28, 1959; May 08, 1961; Sep 18, 1963; Jun 06, 1964; May 20, 1971; Jun 09, 1971*
Winlaw, Joseph: undated
Winningham, Geoff: Dec 10, 1968; Dec 12, 1968*; Dec 20, 1968; Dec 28, 1968*; also see Latent Image (Gallery)
Winokur?, Paula and Bob: Nov 05, 1963
Wisdom: Dec 12, 1956; Dec 24, 1956*
Wiseman, Diane: Apr 12, 1975; May 21, 1975*
Witkin Gallery (Lee Witkin, director): undated; Jan 13, 1969*; Jan 16, 1969; Aug 10, 1969; Sep 26, 1969*; Oct 16, 1969; Oct 18, 1969*; Jan 19, 1970; Apr 22, 1970; May 27, 1970; Jul 31, 1970; Aug 03, 1970*; Aug 08, 1970; Sep 07, 1970*; Sep 12, 1970; Sep 29, 1970; Oct 08, 1970*; Oct 24, 1970*; Oct 27, 1970; Nov 05, 1970*; Nov 06, 1970*; Nov 14, 1970; Nov 22, 1970; Dec 03, 1970*; Dec 08, 1970*; Feb 03, 1971; Feb 10, 1971*; Feb 13, 1971; Mar 27, 1971*; Apr 08, 1971; Apr 26, 1971*; May 02, 1971; Aug 04, 1971; Aug 07, 1971; Nov 09, 1971; Nov 18, 1971; Dec 15, 1971; Dec 17, 1971; Jan 23, 1972; Jan 28, 1972*; Mar 18, 1972; Mar 26, 1972*; Apr 17, 1972; Apr 24, 1972; May 15, 1972*; Dec 06, 1972; Mar 03, 1973; Mar 19, 1973*; Mar 26, 1973*; Mar 29, 1973; Apr 12, 1973; Apr 21, 1973; Apr 23, 1973*; May 09, 1973; May 10, 1973; May 17, 1973*; May 31, 1973; Jun 28, 1973*; Jun 30, 1973; Jul 25, 1973; Sep 05, 1973*; Sep 08, 1973; Sep 19, 1973*; Sep 28, 1973; Oct 17, 1973; Nov 07, 1973*; Nov 11, 1973; Nov 23, 1973; Nov 29, 1973*; Jan 05, 1974 (including letter dated Aug 08, 1973 from the American Foundation for the Blind); Jan 11, 1974*; Feb 07, 1974*; Mar 06, 1974*; Mar 13, 1974*; Mar 20, 1974; Mar 30, 1974; Apr 05, 1974*; Apr 11, 1974; Apr 18, 1974*; Jun 01, 1974*; Sep 07, 1974; Sep 11, 1974*; Oct 15, 1974*; Feb 01, 1975*; Feb 27, 1975*; Apr 12, 1975; Apr 25, 1975; Apr 30, 1975*; May 14, 1975*; Jan 16, 1976; Feb 28, 1976; Mar 29, 1976*; Apr 14, 1976; May 05, 1976*; May 18, 1976; May 27, 1976
Witt, Doreen: Dec 12, 1974
Witt-Diamont, Ruth: Nov 17, 1959*; Nov 30, 1970
Wolman, Baron: [Aug 1972]; Aug 02, 1972*
Wood, Charles Erskine Scott: see Kolisch, Marian Wood
Woods, Gurdon: undated; May 1970; Feb 15, 1971*
Wornum, Michael: Feb 08, 1966*
Worth, Courtia: undated
Worth, Don: Oct 31, 1968; mentioned in letter dated Dec 17, 1970*
Wright, Evelyn: Jan 08, 1973*
Wurlitzer, Pauline: Sep 11, 1958; Sep 11, 1958*; Sep 24, 1958; Nov 05, 1958*; Oct 31, 1960
Wurster, William (Bill): Jun 07, 1967; Jul 15, 1967*; Jul 28, 1967*; Jun 04, 1968*; Jul 04, 1968*; Jan 31, 1969*; Feb 03, 1969; Feb 25, 1969*; Apr 08, 1969; Apr 22, 1969; Apr 15, 1970
Yale University Library: see Stieglitz Archives
Yale University School of Art: Mar 12, 1976; Mar 19, 1976*; Apr 26, 1976
Yamamoto, Norito: Jul 01, 1959*; Sep 24, 1959*
Yao, Shen: see Shen Yao
Yick Contractors: Dec 21, 1966*; Jan 25, 1967*; Feb 25, 1967*
Young, Maple: see Straub, Bernice
Zane, Marjorie: Dec 14, 1967*
Zapton, Steve: see Untitled (gallery)
Zeldin, Karen Dash: undated
Zins, Ronald: Jun 25, 1970; Jun 29, 1970*
Zinszer, Mary Lemoyne: Oct 10, 1947*; Jan 31, 1969*; May 03, 1969*; Aug 07, 1969*; Oct 01, 1969; Nov 14, 1969*; Dec 09, 1969*; Jan 08, 1970*; Dec 23, 1971*
Zlatovski, Jane: see Foster, Jane
Zorach, William: Jan 15, 1960
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
Group f.64
Subjects-Topical:
Photography, Artistic; Portrait photography; Women photographers; Photographers; Photographers -- California -- San Francisco Bay Area
Types of Materials:
Interviews; Illustrated letters; Photographs
Names:
Aalto, Alvar, 1898-1976; Adams, Ansel, 1902-; Andreson, Laura; Bissantz, Edgar, 1901-; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971; Bristol, Horace; Bullock, Wynn; Butler, John Davidson, 1890-1974; Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 1882-1966; Feininger, Lyonel, 1871-1956; Graves, Morris, 1910-; Hellman, Lillian, 1906-; Kanaga, Consuelo, 1894-; Lange, Dorothea; Mann, Margery; Moholy-Nagy, László, 1895-1946; Newhall, Beaumont, 1908-; Newman, Arnold, 1918-; Noskowiak, Sonya, d. 1975; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Partridge, Roi, 1888-1984; Schoener, Allon; Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973; Steinert, Otto, 1915-; Strand, Paul, 1890-1976; Struss, Karl, 1886-; Toklas, Alice B.; Van Dyke, Willard; Weston, Edward, 1886-1958; White, Minor; Witkin, Lee D.; Zorach, William, 1887-1966; George Eastman House; Henry Art Gallery; Witkin Gallery
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by Imogen Cunningham in 1974 and 1976, and by her son, Gryffyd Partridge, in 1991.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on microfilm reels 5034-5041. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1907-1981, undated, Series 1:; (box 1; 4 folders)
  This series includes a hand-written birth certificate signed by Cunningham's parents (1934), an affidavit of birth (1950), five biographical sketches, four award certificates, a diploma for an honorary degree of Doctor of Fine Arts from the California College of Arts and Crafts, and miscellaneous family tree information. A copy of a letter from the Cunningham Family Bible, dated Apr 30, 1956, and a letter from Roger Cunningham dated August 8, 1968 that provides genealogical information, can be found in Series 2: Correspondence.
  - Biographical Material, 1907-1981, (3 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Miscellaneous Family Tree Information, undated, 1970 (Box 1, Reel 5034)
- Correspondence, 1909-1991, undated, Series 2:; (boxes 1-4; 3.6 linear feet)
  Correspondence found in this series is with both family members and business colleagues, reflecting both aspects of Cunningham's life. A list of notable correspondents from these files can be found in the Appendix.
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically with undated correspondence at the beginning of the series, followed by dated correspondence.
  - Unidentified Correspondents, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Surnames Unknown, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Surnames Known, A-P, undated, (4 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Gryffyd Partridge Family, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Padriac Partridge Family, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Roi Partridge, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Rondal Partridge Family, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Surnames Known, P-Z, undated (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Correspondence, 1909-May 1956, (47 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5034)
  - Correspondence, July 1956-1961, (36 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5035)
  - Correspondence, 1962-Sept. 1964, (21 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5035)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1964-Dec. 1968, (46 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5036)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1969-Aug. 1969, (11 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5037)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1969-Sept. 1971, (43 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5037)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1971-Feb. 1974, (39 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5038)
  - Correspondence, March 1974-Jan. 1975, (22 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5038)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1975-1976, (24 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
- Personal Business Records, 1944-1976, Series 3:; (box 4; 15 folders)
  This series consists of legal documents including loan agreements, Cunningham's will, insurance policies, and financial material such as bank account records, check registers, household accounts, and records of the Imogen Cunningham Trust.
  - Legal documents (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Deposit receipts for real estate, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Loan agreements, 1954-1975 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Permission contracts to reproduce art work, 1957-1974 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Imogen Cunningham's will, 1962 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Teaching contracts, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Insurance policies, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Petition for estate of Paula Daveney, 1976 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Financial Material (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Bank account records, 1944-1973 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Check registers, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Sales and gift records, 1954-1975 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Household accounts, 1950-1953 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Stocks, 1957-1970 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Imogen Cunningham Trust (see entry under Correspondence), 1974-1976 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Medical receipts, 1976 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
    - Miscellaneous financial material, undated, 1973 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
- Notes, 1959-1968, Series 4:; (box 4; 10 folders)
  This series includes address books, a notebook, lecture notes, passenger lists, and a packing list for a circulating exhibition.
  - Address books, undated, (4 books in 3 folders) (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Lecture notes, undated (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Passenger lists (2), 1960 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Packing list for circulating exhibition, circa 1965 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Jane Foster's notes: Excerpts from My Ten Years as a Counterspy by Boris Morros, 1959 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Notes on household appliances, undated (Box 4, Reel 5039)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated, 1968 (Box 4, Reel 5039)
- Teaching Files, 1964-1971, Series 5:; (box 5; 4 folders)
  These files contain photographs of students and their critiques of their own work in class. Teaching contracts can be found in Series 3: Personal Business Records.
  - Teaching Files, 1964-1971, (4 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5039)
- Writings, circa 1910-1976, Series 6:; (box 5; 21 folders)
  This series includes essays and speeches by Cunningham and miscellaneous writings by others.
  - Writings by Cunningham (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "About the Direct-Development of Platinum Papers for Brown Tones," circa 1910 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Speech upon receiving California College of Arts and Crafts Degree, 1968 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Miscellaneous writings, undated, 1958 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
  - Writings by Others (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Exhibition captions by unidentified authors, undated (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "Draft Letter: Photographer's Rights" by unidentified author, undated (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "The Aspen Photo Conference" by Beaumont Newhall, 1951 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Script: "Visit with Imogen Cunningham," the Jane Todd Program, KCBS Radio, July 1952 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Script: "Art Festival #2; This is San Francisco," KCBS Radio, September 17, 1955 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "Photography and the Critic" by Margery Mann, 1968 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by Carol Atkins of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by Steve Carr of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by G. Goodger-Hill of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by Jochen W. Hagberg of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by Paul Neevel of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Review by Lynn Reese of book Imogen Cunningham: Photographs, 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Typescript by David Haberstich for exhibition catalog "The Camera and the Human Facade," 1970 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Typescript by Margery Mann for exhibition announcement, 1973 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "Notes on a 'Notebook' " by Peter Nicastro, 1973 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "Imogen in Utopia" by unidentified author, circa 1974 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - Transcript of speech by Ernie Laszlo honoring Dr. Karl Struss, Apr 29, 1974 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
    - "Portrait: Active American - Imogen Cunningham" by Leif Wigh, 1976 (Box 5, Reel 5039)
- Interview Transcripts, 1951, undated, Series 7:; (box 5; 2 folders)
  This series contains transcripts of a video interview and of a radio interview.
  - Unidentified video interview, undated (Box 5, Reel 5039)
  - Radio interview: "Standard Brands, Woman's Magazine of the Air," Apr 20, 1951 (Box 5, Reel 5040)
- Printed Material, 1903-1991, Series 8:; (boxes 5-7; 1.2 linear feet)
  This series include clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, calendars of events, programs, brochures, and reproductions of art work.
  - Clippings, 1913-1991 (Box 5, Reel 5040)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Cunningham, 1914-1971, undated, (13 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5040)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Cunningham, 1971-1981, (3 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5041)